<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Blog</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 17:32:56 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 17:32:56 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dual Boot Ubuntu on SSD and HDD</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has to be a bit of background information so if you are in hurry then jump to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dual Boot Ubuntu on HDD and SSD&lt;/code&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wondering about how much time do we waste on installing softwares on windows. We continue to do this until we realise that we have lost all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, this happened with me too. Since, most of my projects were already setup on windows, I found it difficult to switch because I had to do the settings once again. On being pushed more I decided to switch to WSL because that was a more comfortable option but till when? Duh… 7-8 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was literally frustrated with using WSL because of two major reasons -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its exponentially increasing size (that obviously took a lot of disk space).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Its increasing loading time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday I decided to switch back to Ubuntu and guess what? Today I am here writing this blog on ubuntu with all my java, cpp, shell, ruby and python programs running successfully. Fast, isn’t it ? I suppose that’s because I learn’t a lot of CLI commands while using WSL ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really love it…. I mean working with WSL can sometimes be a serious pain because of lots of installation conflicts but with Linux I feel like living a dream life. I installed Ubuntu on two PCs actually because I could not test the installation directly on my PC(I left my hardisk at college and had to search for a safe option). So, I took my brother’s PC for testing. Well this is a lot of detail…now let’s directly dive into the installation steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dual-boot-ubuntu-on-hdd-and-ssd&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dual Boot Ubuntu on HDD and SSD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do PCs have HDD and SSD ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the scenario: you got a new computer. It comes with a SSD with limited disk space like 120 GB and an additional HDD with 500 GB or 1 TB disk space. This is usually the scene with gaming laptops where large disk space matters for storing game files but SSD is required for faster boot and computing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you want to dual boot on a system with two disks, you may get confused about where should you be installing Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have three options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Linux completely on the SSD. You’ll get full advantage of SSD speed, but then you will have only a limited disk space.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install Linux completely on the HDD. You’ll have plenty of disk space, but Linux will boot slower, and you won’t get the SSD advantage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A compromise between SSD and HDD. You keep the root (and thus swap and boot) on SSD and you put your Home directory on HDD. This way, you boot faster into Linux and you have plenty of disk space for your personal documents and downloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for the 3rd Option and this is what I am going to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things you need in this tutorial:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A computer that comes preinstalled with Windows 10 and has both an SSD and an HDD.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A USB key (pen drive or USB drive) of at least 4 GB in size and no data on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internet connection (for downloading Ubuntu ISO image and live USB creating tool).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optional: External USB disk for making back up of your data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-make-backup-of-your-data&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 1: Make backup of your data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you’ll be dealing with disk partitions, it will be wise to make a copy of your important files on an external disk. This is optional but having a backup is always a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-make-disk-partition-for-ubuntu-installation&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 2: Make disk partition for Ubuntu installation&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Windows menu, search for disk and go to ‘Create and format hard disk partitions’.
You’ll see both SSD and HDD here. You have to shrink both SSD and HDD one by one and make some free space that will be utilized later for installing Ubuntu Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right click on the SSD and choose Shrink Volume option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will give you the largest possible disk partition you can make here. Don’t use it all. Leave some extra space for Windows. I have given it 30 GB which is a decent disk space for the root partition. Anything between 20 and 40 GB is a fair choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-download-ubuntu&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 3: Download Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download Ubuntu Desktop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Ubuntu’s website and download the ISO file. If you need to download Ubuntu via torrents, you can find it under the ‘alternative downloads’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-create-bootable-ubuntu-usb&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 4: Create bootable Ubuntu USB&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily create bootable Ubuntu USB in Windows, Linux and macOS. Since the focus here is on Windows, you can use a Windows specific tool like Rufus. Etcher is also a good tool in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Rufus from its &lt;a href=&quot;https://rufus.ie/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.Plug in your USB. Make sure it doesn’t have any important data because it will be formatted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the Rufus tool. It automatically identifies the plugged in USB but double check it anyway. Then browse to the location of the downloaded ISO image and ensure that it uses GPT partitioning scheme and UEFI target system.Hit the start button and wait for the process to complete. Once you have the live Ubuntu USB ready, the next step is to boot from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-boot-from-the-live-usb&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 5: Boot from the live USB&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may choose to access the UEFI settings when the system starts by pressing F2/F10/F12 button but a more robust way is go through Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the Windows menu, search for UEFI and then click on ‘Change advanced startup options’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Under the Advanced startup option, click on Restart now button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the next screen, click on ‘Use a device’.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize the USB disk with its name and size. It may also be displayed as EFI USB Device.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now it will power off your system and reboot into the disk you chose which should be the live USB disk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-installing-ubuntu-linux&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Step 6: Installing Ubuntu Linux&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have booted from the live USB, you may start the installation procedure. The first few steps are simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You choose the language and keyboard.On the next screen, choose Normal installation. No need to download updates or install third-party software just yet. You may do it after installation completes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After some time you’ll see the Installation type screen. Here, opt for ‘Something else‘ option.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should see the free space you had created earlier on the next screen. Select the free space created on SSD (you can guess by its size if nothing else) and click on the + sign to use this free space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note : These are sample images, not of my PC.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, it will take the entire free space which is a good thing. Keep the partition type primary.
What you need to change is the file system type to Ext4 and mount point to / (/ means root in Linux).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, select the other free space on the HDD and click the + sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time choose Home as the mount point. Partition remains primary and file type ext4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to worry about ‘Device for boot loader installation’. You have a pre-installed Windows UEFI system. You should have an EFI partitioning (ESP) already (for me it’s 100 MB partitioning with type efi). The Ubuntu installer is intelligent and can automatically detect this partition and use it for Grub bootloader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If everything looks good, hit the Install Now button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Things are pretty straightforward from here. Select a timezone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter a username, computer’s name, i.e. hostname and an easy to remember password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now wait for like 7-8 minutes for the installation to finish.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart the system when the installation finishes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll be asked to remove the USB disk. Remove the disk and press enter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If things go right, you should see the black or purple grub screen with option to boot into Ubuntu and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. You can now enjoy both Windows and Linux on the same system with SSD and HDD. Nice, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/linux6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this blog was helpful for you. If you still have questions or if you are facing any issues, please let me know in the comments section, and I’ll try to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/Ubuntu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/Ubuntu/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pre-GSoC experience @ Debian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well this was my first experience of working with a huge project for GSoC 2021.
To be honest I was really late for making contributions to the project as I was waiting for the results of Outreachy but a huge thanks to the developer community of Debian for being very supportive throughout the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, to my surprise there were just a few student developers working on the project(just 3 at that time but they were the ones already involved with the community for long time…which I got to know later) and this saved me from being overwhelmed and I could carry out my work with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view my project proposal &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1gPS0DD3us0_5ecczn9-vZxP8ujcYpJGTsJPomL5X75k/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am quite familiar with git and Github, HTML, C++ and this was the main reason for me choosing this project.
I was able to setup the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://salsa.debian.org/ci-team/debci&quot;&gt;Debian Continuous Integerations&lt;/a&gt; (debci)  within two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I began contributing to the project, I got to know that most of the codes were written in Ruby and Shell. Well this was quite a learning curve for me, I got to fix some of the shellcheck errors and errors in the ruby files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended the meeting for GSoC, got a chance to interact with the mentors and was able to clarify my doubts.
As of now the contribution and proposal submission period is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep you all updated about the status of my application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[ UPDATE ] - I was not selected for GSOC 2021 but this was definitely a very fruitful experience for me. I encourage you all to participate and apply for GSoC next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Be not afraid of greatness: some are born great, some achieve greatness, and some have greatness thrust upon them.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/GSoC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/GSoC/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Export WSL2 to other Drive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL) is a compatibility layer for running Linux binary executables (in ELF format) natively on Windows 10 and Windows Server 2019. If you don’t know what Windows Subsystem for Linux is (WSL from now on in this post), I recommend reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, I shall not only tell you how to setup WSL2 on you blog but I will also guide you about how to move the vhdx(virtual hard disk) file of ubuntu to other drives(Eg - E: or D: instead of C:).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you already have WSL2 installed please move on to step B.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-a---installing-wsl2-on-your-pc&quot;&gt;Step A - Installing WSL2 on your PC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I am going to perform the manual installation steps present on the official docs given &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install-win10&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
The steps mentioned here are same has those mentioned on the official website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1---enable-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux&quot;&gt;Step 1 - Enable the Windows Subsystem for Linux&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must first enable the “Windows Subsystem for Linux” optional feature before installing any Linux distributions on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell as Administrator and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dism.exe /online /enable-feature /featurename:Microsoft-Windows-Subsystem-Linux /all /norestart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2---check-requirements-for-running-wsl-2&quot;&gt;Step 2 - Check requirements for running WSL 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To update to WSL 2, you must be running Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For x64 systems: Version 1903 or higher, with Build 18362 or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For ARM64 systems: Version 2004 or higher, with Build 19041 or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Builds lower than 18362 do not support WSL 2. Use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/software-download/windows10&quot;&gt;Windows Update Assistant&lt;/a&gt; to update your version of Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check your version and build number, select &lt;strong&gt;Windows logo key + R&lt;/strong&gt;, type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;winver&lt;/code&gt;, select OK. Update to the latest Windows version in the Settings menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note :If you are running Windows 10 version 1903 or 1909, open “Settings” from your Windows menu, navigate to “Update &amp;amp; Security” and select “Check for Updates”. Your Build number must be 18362.1049+ or 18363.1049+, with the minor build # over .1049. Read more: WSL 2 Support is coming to Windows 10 Versions 1903 and 1909. See the troubleshooting instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3---enable-virtual-machine-feature&quot;&gt;Step 3 - Enable Virtual Machine feature&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before installing WSL 2, you must enable the Virtual Machine Platform optional feature. Your machine will require virtualization capabilities to use this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell as Administrator and run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dism.exe /online /enable-feature /featurename:VirtualMachinePlatform /all /norestart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restart your machine to complete the WSL install and update to WSL 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-4---download-the-linux-kernel-update-package&quot;&gt;Step 4 - Download the Linux kernel update package&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download the latest package:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wslstorestorage.blob.core.windows.net/wslblob/wsl_update_x64.msi&quot;&gt;WSL2 Linux kernel update package for x64 machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Note: If you’re using an ARM64 machine, please download the ARM64 package instead. If you’re not sure what kind of machine you have, open Command Prompt or PowerShell and enter: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systeminfo | find &quot;System Type&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Caveat: On non-English Windows versions, you might have to modify the search text, for example, in German it would be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;systeminfo | find &quot;Systemtyp&quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Run the update package downloaded in the previous step. (Double-click to run - you will be prompted for elevated permissions, select ‘yes’ to approve this installation.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the installation is complete, move on to the next step - setting WSL 2 as your default version when installing new Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-5---set-wsl-2-as-your-default-version&quot;&gt;Step 5 - Set WSL 2 as your default version&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open PowerShell and run this command to set WSL 2 as the default version when installing a new Linux distribution:
PowerShell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wsl --set-default-version 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-6---install-your-linux-distribution-of-choice&quot;&gt;Step 6 - Install your Linux distribution of choice&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the Microsoft Store and select your favorite Linux distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View of Linux distributions in the Microsoft Store&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he following links will open the Microsoft store page for each distribution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9pjn388hp8c9&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 16.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9N9TNGVNDL3Q&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 18.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9n6svws3rx71&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04 LTS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9NJFZK00FGKV&quot;&gt;openSUSE Leap 15.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9MZ3D1TRP8T1&quot;&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 12 SP5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PN498VPMF3Z&quot;&gt;SUSE Linux Enterprise Server 15 SP1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9PKR34TNCV07&quot;&gt;Kali Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9MSVKQC78PK6&quot;&gt;Debian GNU/Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9n6gdm4k2hnc&quot;&gt;Fedora Remix for WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9NV1GV1PXZ6P&quot;&gt;Pengwin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9N8LP0X93VCP&quot;&gt;Pengwin Enterprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9p804crf0395&quot;&gt;Alpine WSL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the distribution’s page, select “Get”.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;400&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/media/ubuntustore.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you launch a newly installed Linux distribution, a console window will open and you’ll be asked to wait for a minute or two for files to de-compress and be stored on your PC. All future launches should take less than a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will then need to &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/user-support&quot;&gt;create a user account and password for your new Linux distribution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/media/ubuntuinstall.png&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CONGRATULATIONS! You’ve successfully installed and set up a Linux distribution that is completely integrated with your Windows operating system!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;step-b---moving-wsl2-vhdx&quot;&gt;Step B - Moving WSL2 vhdx&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using Windows 10 version 1903 (April 2019 Update) or later, you can try the WSL command line tool with the export and import options. If you are using an older Windows 10 version, you can move the distribution to another drive using lxRunOffline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;using-the-wsl-command-line-tool&quot;&gt;Using the WSL command line tool&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Windows 10 version 1903 (April 2019 Update) or later, you can use the wsl.exe command line tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Export the distribution. Create a .tar file with the distribution to move using wsl.exe –export&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wsl.exe --export &amp;lt;DistributionName&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Tar-FileName&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to export an Ubuntu distribution, you can use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\&amp;gt; wsl.exe --export Ubuntu c:\data\ubuntu.tar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Import the distribution into the target folder. Then, you can import the exported distribution into another folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;wsl.exe --import &amp;lt;DistributionName&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Folder-To-Install&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Tar-FileName&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to import the exported Ubuntu into a new UbuntuCustom distribution, you can use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\&amp;gt; wsl.exe --import UbuntuCustom d:\wsl\UbuntuCustom c:\data\ubuntu.tar
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: You may check an script for moving WSL distros that use these commands at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pxlrbt/move-wsl&quot;&gt;https://github.com/pxlrbt/move-wsl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;using-lxrunoffline&quot;&gt;Using LxRunOffline&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any Windows 10 version, you can move the distribution to another drive using lxRunOffline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set permissions to the target folder. First, I think you must set some permissions to the folder where the distribution will be moved. You may use icacls &lt;dir&gt; /grant &quot;&lt;user&gt;:(OI)(CI)(F)&quot; to set the proper permissions.&lt;/user&gt;&lt;/dir&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\&amp;gt; whoami
test\jaime

C:\&amp;gt; icacls D:\wsl /grant &quot;jaime:(OI)(CI)(F)&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: In addition to the above permissions, I have activated the long path names in Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the distribution. Using lxrunoffline move.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\wsl&amp;gt; lxrunoffline move -n Ubuntu-18.04 -d d:\wsl\installed\Ubuntu-18.04
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may check the installation folder using&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\wsl&amp;gt; lxrunoffline get-dir -n Ubuntu-18.04
d:\wsl\installed\Ubuntu-18.04
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the distribution. after moving the distribution, you can run the distribution using wsl or the same &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lxrunoffline&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\wsl&amp;gt; lxrunoffline run -n Ubuntu-18.04 -w
user@test:~$ exit
logout

C:\wsl&amp;gt; wsl
user@test:/mnt/c/wsl$ exit
logout
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WoW! You were successfully able to image the virtual harddisk of WSL2 to other drive.
Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/WSL2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/WSL2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AdobeWiT Scholarship Interview Experience-2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Adobe0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Adobe WIT Scholarship is an opportunity presented to undergraduate girls currently pursuing their third year in a Computer Science or related stream. The aim of the scholarship is to encourage more girls and women to explore the field of technology and reduce the existing gender gap in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scholarship offers several benefits including mentoring by a senior technology leader at Adobe, an opportunity to be considered for an internship at Adobe, a conference ticket to GHCI and funding for the candidate’s remaining tuition fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the eligibility criteria and benefits of the Adobe WIT Scholarship &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.adobe.com/adobe-india-women-in-technology-scholarship/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scholarship-details&quot;&gt;Scholarship Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scholarship will cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fund toward tuition fees for the remainder of the award recipient’s university education ending in academic year 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity for Summer Internship at Adobe India in 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentoring by a senior technology leader from Adobe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel to Grace Hopper Conference India, including participation fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A committee of Adobe researchers will be reviewing all applicants and will choose the recipients at their discretion. Recipients are selected based on their research (creative, impactful, important, and realistic in scope), how their work would contribute to Adobe, their technical skills (ability to build complex computer programs), and their personal skills (problem-solving ability, communication, leadership, organizational skills, ability to work in teams).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students may be invited for phone interviews for internship opportunities prior to Fellowship winner selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;application-process&quot;&gt;Application process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial application consists of submitting a resume, answering 5-6 essay type questions (the word limit ranges from 200-250 words) and a letter of recommendation from your college professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about the application process, there are 5 parts to the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-basic-information&quot;&gt;1. Basic Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part includes filling up basic details about your course, university, CGPA, contact information and research areas of interest. (I would recommend reading up about the advancements in the research areas you’ve mentioned and have thorough knowledge of the subject.) The research areas I had mentioned were Machine Learning, BCI, and Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-essays&quot;&gt;2. Essays&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 5 essay-based questions, all of which you were expected to write in under 200 words. These essays intend to understand your personality, why you’re interested in the field of technology, your goals, the difficulties you’ve faced as a woman in technology, your role model and of course why you think you deserve this scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While writing these answers, don’t hesitate to mention your achievements or failures, but make sure, to be honest. Craft a story that can describe who you are, your interests and passion, and do not try to answer it superficially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your answers shall speak more about what you are now rather that what you want to become or achieve in future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-resume&quot;&gt;3. Resume&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My resume had a combination of my important academic grades, work experience (internships), projects, achievements, positions of responsibility &amp;amp; certifications. Here is a tip - Try to keep your resume short and limit it to a single page. Choose the projects carefully because this is where most of your discussions shall be focused on. Also, make sure that you mention those projects that have a significant impact and deal with reallife scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, make sure to be honest, in your resume about your achievements &amp;amp; projects, because both my interviews were based on the things I had listed in my resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-academic-transcripts&quot;&gt;4. Academic Transcripts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had included my semester grade cards (the first three semesters whose results were published) &amp;amp; my 12th and 10th certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-letter-of-recommendation&quot;&gt;5. Letter of Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approach a professor from college who knows you personally(and can write a good LOR - Yes it does help in strengthening your application) and request for a letter of recommendation. Try and request in advance, because chances are, your professor could be giving recommendations for a lot of people from your institution as well. So, ensure that, you give the professor sufficient buffer time to submit the letter by the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-multimedia&quot;&gt;6. Multimedia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also an additional multimedia (video) submission link. But it’s completely up to you to decide whether to submit one or not. I decided to submit one.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-second-interview&quot;&gt;My Second Interview&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Adobe-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Don’t choose your inspiration solely because you think it will appeal to others. You are going to live with this play for some time—maybe years—so you should base your work on one that speaks to you.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received this mail within a week or two after the first interview and needless to say, I was on cloud nine. My second interview was scheduled on December 3, 2020. The second interview was also quite similar to the first one except for the fact that it had a more detailed discussion and was focused mainly on a single project rather that a variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I feel really grateful to be interviewed by one of the &lt;strong&gt;technology specialists at Adobe, &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.adobe.com/person/atanu-sinha/&quot;&gt;Mr. Atanu R Sinha&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; The interview was, in itself, a huge opportunity and I feel blessed to be interacting with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview began with my introduction and about how the online classes are going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about the project you wish to discuss.(Again choose this wisely- The second interview is going to be a tough one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many follow up questions regarding the project  and they were quite detailed(peace…). I was able to answer most of the questions decently but there were 1-2 questions, that I never thought of, would be related to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interviewer was kind enough to explain me the different aspects in which I could explain the project and we had an in depth discussion covering the different use cases of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most motivating aspects of this interview was that I really became comfortable in explaining my approach smoothly and made sure that my interviewer understands each and everything that I say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming to the programming part, I explained the codes to the interviewer and he seemed satisfied with my answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I asked a few questions from him regarding Adobe products and the different phases through which each project goes through in order to become a final end user product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This interview again lasted for 45 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not very satisfied with my performance. I could identify some of the areas in which my interview did not go up to the mark and I needed to focus on some areas of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(P.S.- This was probably the final interview and I could not clear it but I learnt a lot from it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interview concluded on 3rd December and the scholarship results were declared on 11 December, 2020.
There were a total of 6 talented scholarship winners this year(See the list &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.adobe.com/adobe-india-women-in-technology-scholarship/india-scholarship-winners/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)  and I congratulate them on their achievement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any specific questions, feel free to ask them in comment section. I’ll try my level best to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay safe and healthy. All the best ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Adobewit-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Adobewit-2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>AdobeWiT Scholarship Interview Experience-1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Adobe0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Adobe WIT Scholarship is an opportunity presented to undergraduate girls currently pursuing their third year in a Computer Science or related stream. The aim of the scholarship is to encourage more girls and women to explore the field of technology and reduce the existing gender gap in the tech industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scholarship offers several benefits including mentoring by a senior technology leader at Adobe, an opportunity to be considered for an internship at Adobe, a conference ticket to GHCI and funding for the candidate’s remaining tuition fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the eligibility criteria and benefits of the Adobe WIT Scholarship &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.adobe.com/adobe-india-women-in-technology-scholarship/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scholarship-details&quot;&gt;Scholarship Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scholarship will cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fund toward tuition fees for the remainder of the award recipient’s university education ending in academic year 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opportunity for Summer Internship at Adobe India in 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentoring by a senior technology leader from Adobe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel to Grace Hopper Conference India, including participation fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A committee of Adobe researchers will be reviewing all applicants and will choose the recipients at their discretion. Recipients are selected based on their research (creative, impactful, important, and realistic in scope), how their work would contribute to Adobe, their technical skills (ability to build complex computer programs), and their personal skills (problem-solving ability, communication, leadership, organizational skills, ability to work in teams).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students may be invited for phone interviews for internship opportunities prior to Fellowship winner selection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;application-process&quot;&gt;Application process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial application consists of submitting a resume, answering 5-6 essay type questions (the word limit ranges from 200-250 words) and a letter of recommendation from your college professor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking about the application process, there are 5 parts to the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-basic-information&quot;&gt;1. Basic Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part includes filling up basic details about your course, university, CGPA, contact information and research areas of interest. (I would recommend reading up about the advancements in the research areas you’ve mentioned and have thorough knowledge of the subject.) The research areas I had mentioned were Machine Learning, BCI, and Robotics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-essays&quot;&gt;2. Essays&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 5 essay-based questions, all of which you were expected to write in under 200 words. These essays intend to understand your personality, why you’re interested in the field of technology, your goals, the difficulties you’ve faced as a woman in technology, your role model and of course why you think you deserve this scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While writing these answers, don’t hesitate to mention your achievements or failures, but make sure, to be honest. Craft a story that can describe who you are, your interests and passion, and do not try to answer it superficially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your answers should speak more about what you are now rather that what you want to become or achieve in future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-resume&quot;&gt;3. Resume&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My resume had a combination of my important academic grades, work experience (internships), projects, achievements, positions of responsibility &amp;amp; certifications. Here is a tip - Try to keep your resume short and limit it to a single page. Choose the projects carefully because this is where most of your discussions shall be focused on. Also, make sure that you mention those projects that have a significant impact and deal with real-life scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, make sure to be honest, in your resume about your achievements &amp;amp; projects, because both my interviews were based on the things I had listed in my resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-academic-transcripts&quot;&gt;4. Academic Transcripts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had included my semester marksheets (the first three semesters whose results were published) &amp;amp; my 12th and 10th certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-letter-of-recommendation&quot;&gt;5. Letter of Recommendation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approach a professor from college who knows you personally(and can write a good LOR - Yes it does help in strengthening your application) and request for a letter of recommendation. Try and request in advance, because chances are, your professor could be giving recommendations for a lot of people from your institution as well. So, ensure that, you give the professor sufficient buffer time to submit the letter by the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-multimedia&quot;&gt;6. Multimedia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also an additional multimedia (video) submission link. But it’s completely up to you to decide whether to submit one or not. I decided to submit one.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-dream-e-mail&quot;&gt;The Dream E-Mail&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Adobe-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I literally applied to for the scholarship with &lt;strong&gt;I am not going to make it but there is no harm in trying&lt;/strong&gt; kind of attitude and on that day when I saw this email, I could not believe my eyes. I was quite excited and nervous about the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was I woke my mom and told her about the email. She was so happy that she hugged me! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next thing that I did was to reply to the e-mail to schedule the interview. Since I got a lot of days to choose from, I chose 23 November for my interview. Next I began preparing for the interview. I saw a lot of videos of previous scholars and started reiterating on my essays and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interview-day&quot;&gt;Interview Day&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was 23 November 2020, my interview was scheduled in the afternoon between 1:00 p.m. and 1:30 p.m. The platform was bluejeans(almost all the interviews of adobe take place on this platform).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please introduce yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me something about your background and what are the projects you have worked on in college?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do you enjoy working on that technology? What about it excites you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which of the projects you’ve mentioned are you most proud of and why? &lt;strong&gt;(Most important)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with discussing the hardware projects. I ws asked about the ICs(since I mentioned about an IR sensing bot). Then I was asked to tell me about the roadblocks for the project.(This discussion lasted around 5 minutes and the interviewer was quite happy with my response).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can you explain some of the projects that you mentioned ?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please explain the workflow of the project. (I choose encephalophone - one of my ongoing research project)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began discussing the details of the project.The interviewer became quite interested in the project and we had a very detailed discussion on the different aspects of the project. (This discussion lasted around 25 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mention some instances when you’ve had to lead a team to solve a particular technological problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which of the following projects were done as a team? How was the experience?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answers the above two questions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my team had won a hackathon at my college, I began discussing the my hackathon project and then I showed the live demonstration of the project. Then I was asked a few questions and I answered them all nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do you want this scholarship?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any questions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked the interviewer about his idea of an ideal candidate. Also,I knew it was a great opportunity to know about the workculture of Adobe so I asked the same question as a followup to the previous one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This 30 minutes(to be) interview lasted for around 47-50 minutes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed interacting with the interviewer. This was a very fruitful experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was quite happy with my interview. At that point of time I would have never thought that I would clear this interview and qualify for the next interview but I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be sharing my 2nd interview experience in my next blog. If you have any specific questions, feel free to ask them in comment section. I’ll try my level best to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till then… Stay tuned and be safe ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Adobewit-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Adobewit-1/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My internship at The Sparks Foundation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://camo.githubusercontent.com/d61800e0293a2d29f1b65dd9284c0bc60d89fb98eca567ccfc9c34fd5d620119/68747470733a2f2f7777772e746865737061726b73666f756e646174696f6e73696e6761706f72652e6f72672f696d616765732f6c6f676f5f736d616c6c2e706e67&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked as an intern for The Sparks foundation.
In this blog I am going to summarize all the tasks that I completed while working as an intern for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thesparksfoundationsingapore.org/&quot;&gt;The Sparks Foundation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this internship, we were provided a total of 6 Tasks and I was able to successfully complete all the 6 tasks within the given time-frame. All the tasks can be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks&quot;&gt;github Repository.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internship Category&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Data Science and Business&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1 Month&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Work from&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Analytics&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;October-2020&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-1--prediction-using-supervised-ml-level---beginner&quot;&gt;Task-1 : Prediction using Supervised ML (Level - Beginner)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-1_Linear_Regression.ipynb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Predict the percentage of marks of an student based on the number of study hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is a simple linear regression task as it involves just 2 variables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/w&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can use R, Python, SAS Enterprise Miner or any other tool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What will be predicted score if a student studies for 9.25 hrs/ day?
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ePDA-9p19fw&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-2--prediction-using-unsupervised-ml-level---beginner&quot;&gt;Task-2 : Prediction using Unsupervised ML (Level - Beginner)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-2_Clustering.ipynb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the given ‘Iris’ dataset, predict the optimum number of clusters and represent it visually.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use R or Python or perform this task.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3cGyP8j&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/3cGyP8j&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uv-d6PRphp4&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-3--prediction-using-decision-tree-algorithmlevel---intermediate&quot;&gt;Task-3 : Prediction using Decision Tree Algorithm(Level - Intermediate)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-3_Decision_Tree.ipynb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the given ‘Iris’ dataset, create the Decision Tree classifier and visualize it graphically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The purpose is if we feed any new data to this classifier, it would be able to predict the right class accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3kXTdox&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/3kXTdox&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VlBGJgLoGIc&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-4--stock-market-prediction-using-numerical-and-textual-analysis-level---advanced&quot;&gt;Task-4 : Stock Market Prediction using Numerical and Textual Analysis (Level - Advanced)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-4_Stock_Price.ipynb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE : If you face any issue over dataset then please refer to the thread of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/issues/2&quot;&gt;Issue #2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a hybrid model for stock price/performance prediction using numerical analysis of historical stock prices, and sentimental analysis of news headlines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stock to analyze and predict SENSEX (S&amp;amp;P BSE SENSEX)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download historical stock prices from &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/?guccounter=1&quot;&gt;finance.yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download textual (news) data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/36fFPI6&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/36fFPI6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use either R or Python, or both for separate analysis and then combine the findings to create a hybrid model.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sL00unmrVKU&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-5--to-explore-business-analytics-level---beginner--intermediate&quot;&gt;Task-5 : To Explore Business Analytics (Level - Beginner &amp;amp; Intermediate)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-5_Superstore.xlsx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Perform ‘Exploratory Data Analysis’ on the provided dataset ‘SampleSuperstore’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a business manager, try to find out the weak areas where you can work to make more profit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What all business problems you can derive by exploring the data?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can choose any of the tool of your choice (Python/R/Tableau/PowerBI/Excel)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dataset link :&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3i4rbWl&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/3i4rbWl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create storyboards. Screen record along with your audio explaining the charts and interpretations.
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/N4AFlnEoigk&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-6--timeline-analysis--covid-19-level---advanced&quot;&gt;Task-6 : Timeline Analysis : Covid-19 (Level - Advanced)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Sparks-Foundation-Tasks/blob/master/Task-6_Covid19.twb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view my solution.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a storyboard showing spread of Covid 19 cases in your country or any region (Asia, Europe, BRICS etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use animation, timeline and annotations to create attractive and interactive dashboards and story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identify interesting patterns and possible reasons helping Covid 19 spread with basic as well as advanced charts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use Tableau or Power BI for this task&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen record the completed storyboard along with your audio explaining the charts and giving recommendations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dataset: Daily updated .csv file on &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/30d2gdi&quot;&gt;https://bit.ly/30d2gdi&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PLASL3p3i3Y&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view all the tasks on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLWA7Ml8Rq3KfV6QSeO_Hr9t0xbfc-Xdg2&quot;&gt;youtube playlist&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references--&quot;&gt;References -&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.tableau.com/v2018.3/offline/en-us/tableau_desktop.pdf&quot;&gt;Tableau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scikit-learn.org/stable/&quot;&gt;Scikit Learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Sparks-intern/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Sparks-intern/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting up this blog theme</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wondering how I created this blog?&lt;br /&gt;
Wait !&lt;br /&gt;
Before that, tell me, do you know what a blog is?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t, then you’ve come to the right place. A blog is more of a personal diary that people shared online. In this online journal, you can talk about your daily life or share about things that you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog I shall walk you through the details of how I created this blog site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;300&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;https://www.wpbeginner.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/07/whatisblog.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog theme that I used is a Jekyll theme named &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllthemes.io/theme/thinkspace&quot;&gt;Thinkspace&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a static site generator that you can use to create simple sites or blogs and Github pages is a static site hosting service. By using Jekyll with Github pages, you can quite easily put together your first blog/website for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some requirements for jekyll. Did I forget to mention that Jekyll is a Ruby gem? Well now you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a Linux machine you can directly install both the requirements using CLI(Command line Interface) but for windows 
we will have to make certain arrangements for jekyll.To setup jekyll on windows you need to have windows package manager &lt;strong&gt;chocolatey&lt;/strong&gt; installed and from this you can install ruby and gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the steps in &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.arwsoft.id/2016easiest-way-to-install-jekyll-on-windows-using-chocolatey&quot;&gt;this blog&lt;/a&gt; to setup your work environment.Make sure to add chocolatey to path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets move on to creating our blog website using this theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1--install-jekyll-on-your-machine&quot;&gt;Step-1 : Install Jekyll on your machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open windows powershell.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before installing jekyll, we need to ensure the correct version of ruby is installed on the machine because jekyll runs on ruby. (Ruby version must be 2.1 or higher)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check the version of ruby installed, type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruby -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now we need to check if the right version of gem is installed. To check the version of gem, type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, you need to go ahead and install jekyll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To install jekyll, type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should fetch all the jekyll files needed and install them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the installation is done, check the version of jekyll installed by typing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The output should be something like the one given below. The version need not be same. Make sure that you install the latest version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;100&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; src=&quot;../../assets/images/Powershell.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-create-a-jekyll-blog-on-your-local-machine&quot;&gt;Step 2: Create a Jekyll Blog on your local machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name of the blog I’m going to create is Thinkspace and I’ll be demonstrating the following example with this name. Remember to change the name of your blog accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets change the directory using the below code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd &amp;lt;path-to-directory-for-blog&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to create a jekyll blog on local machine, open terminal and type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll new thinkspace
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will create a new folder on your computer for the blog. The folder’s name will be thinkspace (or the name you had entered).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now just search for “thinkspace” to locate the folder on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note : For the upcoming steps if the preceeding commands do nto work then clone &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heiswayi/thinkspace&quot;&gt;this repository&lt;/a&gt; and make changes to this repository instead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to edit the contents of this blog and publish it, I’m going to be using Visual Studio Code. This piece of software lets you use the terminal from the window, making it super easy to view all the files and edit it accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we proceed towards figuring out how to edit the contents, let’s first publish the blog locally and see how it appears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do this, go to the terminal within VSC and type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run into error then clone &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/heiswayi/thinkspace&quot;&gt;this repository.&lt;/a&gt; and perform the steps mentioned :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is still error then check the gemfile in your repository and resolve the version conflicts by installing the mentioned versions in gemfile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now make edits to this repository instead and don’t forget to delete .gitignore file of this repository before uploading code to github because this .gitignore cooresponds to the repository you cloned and not the .gitignore file of your github repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your site should be up and running on your local host: http://127.0.0.1:4000/
Meaning, if you go to this link, you’ll be able to see your blog somewhat like the one mentioned below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/images/host.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s now checkout the different folders that jekyll has created and understand how to edit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt;: This is the folder that has all your blog posts. Each of these posts should be a markdown file and should be included within this folder for it to be listed in your blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;: This files in this folder are responsible for compiling your blog. You basically have different blog posts, images, pages lying in different folders. The files in _sites folder bring them together and publish it as a website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;: This file contains your site’s variables such as title, your usernames, urls etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;about.md&lt;/code&gt;: This is just a markdown file that contains data to be published in your about section&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gemfile&lt;/code&gt;: gemfile contains all the dependencies for this site. Meaning you are using jekyll. And within jekyll, you are using it’s default theme called ‘Minima’. The gem file specifies such info.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quickly make your blog ‘yours’ by adding info relevant to you, edit the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title, description and other details in _config.yml&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content in about.md file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Content in the blog post within _posts folder. You may also copy paste that file and edit its content to create your second blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now your blog website is ready to be published using github pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details on how to publish site using github pages check &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@svinkle/publish-and-share-your-own-website-for-free-with-github-2eff049a1cb5&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Coding ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Blog/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Winning Project @ Electrothon 2k20</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project titled &lt;strong&gt;The Conurbation Algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; is aimed at developing a fully functional featured city without disrupting the ecological density of the city. It was the winning project of my first hackathon &lt;strong&gt;Electrothon 2k20&lt;/strong&gt; at NIT Hamirpur. It is a further modification of the initial &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/josauder/procedural_city_generation&quot;&gt;city generation model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog I shall give a brief overview of the workflow of this project. I am &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; going &lt;strong&gt;to touch the coding part&lt;/strong&gt; as of now so as to prevent the things from being more complicated to comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/Random-Password-Generator/blob/master/LICENSE&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/github/license/DAVFoundation/captain-n3m0.svg?style=flat-square&quot; alt=&quot;license&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/ProjectStatus-Completed-orange&quot; alt=&quot;Project Status&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.repostatus.org/#active&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.repostatus.org/badges/latest/active.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Project Status: Active – The project has reached a stable, usable state and is being actively developed.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Python-3.5%7C3.6%7C3.7-success&quot; alt=&quot;Python Badge&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.shields.io/badge/Dependencies-NumPy%20%7C%20PyQt5%20%7C%20Blender%20%7C%20Scipy%20%7C%20Matplotlib-ff69b4&quot; alt=&quot;Dependency&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/Bl%204.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;challenges-&quot;&gt;Challenges :&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migrating the the code from PyQt4 to PyQt5 and updating the code with the new dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automating the Blender Scripts to run directly from the PyQt5 GUI.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning the code to remove all the version conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generating the new map to run the test scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updating and modifying the codes for growth rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;input--&quot;&gt;Input -&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The input to the conurbation algorithm is the map generated from the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/Land-Stratification-ISRO/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;Land Stratification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/Land-Stratification-ISRO/master/Binary_mosaic.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The growth rule image defines the formation of road network of the town that is created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well we need a road network to traverse across the town, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue color implies a radial growth rule(roads originate from a single junction), red colour indicates grid growth rule(like we have in properly planned cities-proper block division) and green colour depicts organic(random) growth rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/11.png&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dependencies--&quot;&gt;Dependencies -&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Python 3.x&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numpy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PyQt5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scipy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;workflow--&quot;&gt;Workflow -&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/workflow.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;steps-to-replicate-the-program&quot;&gt;Steps to replicate the Program&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clone this repository&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change all the paths in the files &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/blob/master/src/GUI.py&quot;&gt;GUI.py&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/blob/master/src/procedural_city_generation/visualization/blenderize.py&quot;&gt;blenderize.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove all the &lt;strong&gt;pycache&lt;/strong&gt; files from the cloned folder if present.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check all the installed dependencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install and add blender to the environment path.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the script &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/blob/master/src/GUI.py&quot;&gt;GUI.py&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If everything worked so far, the PyQt5 window should openup and the algorithm should generate the city with the clicks.Make sure to run all the tabs in order,i.e., Roadmap Generation-&amp;gt; Polygon Extraction -&amp;gt; Building Generation -&amp;gt;Visualise in Blender.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to experiment with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/tree/master/src/procedural_city_generation/inputs/rule_pictures&quot;&gt;growth rule images&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/tree/master/src/procedural_city_generation/inputs/density_pictures&quot;&gt;Density images&lt;/a&gt; and open a pull request for further modification of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sample-outputs-&quot;&gt;Sample Outputs-&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-roadmap-generation&quot;&gt;1. Roadmap Generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/1.PNG&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-polygon-extraction&quot;&gt;2. Polygon Extraction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/2.PNG&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-building-generation&quot;&gt;3. Building Generation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/3.PNG&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-3d-visualisation-of-buildings-in-blender&quot;&gt;4. 3D Visualisation of Buildings in Blender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kritika-srivastava/The-Conurbation-Algorithm/master/img/Bl%204.PNG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references--&quot;&gt;References -&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.blender.org/api/current/index.html&quot;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.bccnsoft.com/docs/PyQt5/&quot;&gt;PyQt5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/josauder/procedural_city_generation&quot;&gt;City generation Algorithm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/Electrothon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/Electrothon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
